在最后几节讲座中，我们研究了图像形成的过程
In the last couple of lectures, we've looked at the process of image formation, that's
我们如何将3D世界转变为二维图像或该世界的表现形式。该
how we transform the 3D world, into a two-dimensional image or representation of that world. The
对于动物来说，世界的实际三维结构确实非常重要
actual three-dimensional structure of the world is really, really important, for animals
以及机器人。所以在动物的情况下，如果你想象你是一个掠夺性的动物，
as well as for robots. So in the case of animals, if you imagine that you are a predatory animal,
了解猎物有多远是非常重要的。如果你是猎物，那就是它
it's really important to know how far away the prey is. If you're a prey animal it's
知道捕食者有多远是非常重要的。如果你是一个机器人，你可能会
really important to know how far away the predator is. If you're a robot, you might
想知道你想要到达和抓住的物体有多远。如果你是一个手机
want to know how far away is the object that you want to reach and grab. If you're a mobile
机器人，你想知道你前面的空间的哪些部分有物体粘在一起
robot, you want to know which parts of the space in front of you have got objects sticking
高于地面，阻止你在那里和世界的哪个地方开车
up above the ground, that prevent you from driving there and which parts of the world
没有那些障碍。
are free from those kinds of obstacles.
所以我们希望拥有世界的三维结构，但我们只有二维结构
So we want to have a three dimensional structure of the world, but we've only got a two dimensional
代表性投射。我们如何解决这个问题？当人类看待一个人
representational projection. How do we solve this problem? When human beings look at a
二维图像或照片，我们想象三维结构和
two dimensional image or a photograph, we imagine the three dimensional structure and
来自我们对3D世界的体验，我们通过我们获得的体验
that comes from our experience of 3D worlds, the experiences that we've gain through our
整个人生。我将谈谈人类的一些机制
whole lives. And I'm going to talk a little bit about some of the mechanism by which human
众生填补了这个缺失的维度。特别是我将谈论双目
beings fill in this missing dimension. In particular I'm going to talk about binocular
立体声，这就是我们从两个摄像头获取信息的方式，比如我们的两只眼睛
stereo and that's how we take information from two cameras, like the two eyes that we
在我们的头脑中，重新创造三维世界。这是非常普遍的
have in our heads and recreate three dimensional world from that. And this is a very common
机器人技术称为“立体视觉”。
technique in robotics called "Stereo Vision".